

CONTACT



Address London, UK



Phone +44 7490 200 466



Email nicholas.newell@protonmail.ch



in/nicholasdnewellwebdeveloper



Twitter https://twitter.com/nicholasdnewell



https://github.com/ndnewell



Firebase

Portfolio https://ndnewell.github.io/portfolio

SUMMARY

Having always had a fascination with technology and after years of experience ranging from sales to education. I am transitioning into front-end web development so that I may engage in leading edge technological development, use my creative skills in productive ways, and make or add to a substantial product or service that creates positive change in the world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript HTML5 CSS3 iQuery Knockout.js (MVVM) **Bootstrap** GitHub Performance Optimization **TDD** Responsive Design Grunt

NICHOLAS D. NEWELL

Working rights in EU and US / Willing to relocate

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

MAY 2016 UdaciFeeds - http://goo.gl/uNwZ5v

- Completed testing suite using Jasmine for an incomplete project by writing tests that pass.
- Created tests that check form completion, menu changes, and proper loading of elements.
- Wrote tests that determined if web application loops and URLs function properly

FEB 2016 SurfList - https://goo.gl/TbEmgb

- From scratch, single-page, responsive app using Knockout.js and jQuery that allows users to search for surf breaks
- Utilized firebase for hosting, authentication, and backend data
- Implemented third party APIs via AJAX data requests.

JUN 2015

Website Optimization - http://goo.gl/N04vuB

- Optimized critical rendering path of existing website (Cam's profile) to achieve PageSpeed Insights score above 90.
- Eliminated inefficiencies in the website's (Cam's Pizzeria) scroll animation (pizza.html). Site now scrolls at 60 frames per second
- Used JavaScript task runner Grunt in build process.

MAR 2015

Cartman Crush - http://goo.gl/h6ordi

- Clone of the classic game, Frogger.
- Coded player, enemies, relic subclasses using object prototype
- Used HTML5 Canvas for game animation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MAY 2014 - MAR 2015

English Language Educator

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology – Hanoi, Vietnam

- Presented workshops focusing on writing for university and supported students via a university help desk.
- Taught across all levels in the academic English program, with a focus on research & report writing for academia.
- Led business English classes for locally based firms & taught government diplomatic officials job-related English.
- Successfully integrated the use of about 6 new educational technology tools into teaching approach.

DEC 2012 - APR 2014

English Language Instructor

- Led upper level reading and essay/report writing lectures, with a focus on general argumentative logic.
- Nominated teacher of the year in 2013.
- Utilized web technologies for teaching students and supporting colleagues



WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

DEC 2011 - NOV 2012

English Language Teacher

ILA Vietnam – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Taught General English to all ages in classrooms of 12 19 students, using a student centred approach.
- Increased student participation, using culturally relevant contexts.
- Created new behaviour management techniques, resulting in an increase in overall student output.

OCT 2008 - MAR 2011 Marketing Sales Manager

SUPA-T Green Tea - Sydney, Australia

- Implemented local distribution, sales, and field marketing efforts in and around Sydney and key areas of NSW.
- Successfully acquired 2 major distributors in the Australian market, allowing broader access to cross-country markets.
- Managed the design and provided the copy for the company website, adding appeal to existing sales points.



EDUCATION & ACTIVITIES

OCT 2014 - MAY 2016 Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

Udacity - Global

MAR 2014 - AUG 2014 **Cert ICT (Distinction)**

Cambridge English - Hanoi, Vietnam

APR 2011 - MAR 2012 **YL Extension**

Cambridge English – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

OCT 2011 - NOV 2011 **CELTA (Pass B)**

Cambridge English – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

AUG 2002 - MAY 2006 German B.A. / Minor Business

University of Colorado - Boulder, Colorado, USA

DEC 2002 - MAY 2006 Founder of the University of Colorado chapter

Sigma Alpha Epsilon - Boulder, Colorado, USA